Lance Madden

Digital Marketer and Web Development Aficionado, with a passion for Sales

Rockport, MA 01966 lance@gloucestermassmarketing.com +1 978 704 5900

Greetings, human!

I am a passionate web developer & programmer, as well as the Founder of Gloucester Mass Marketing, thanks for taking a minute to read!

When I was in 3rd grade, another student tapped two wire-ends from a Christmas Tree bulb to a battery I was carrying, the bulb lit up, and my whole world changed.

Since then, I've been working in Computer Engineering, and more specifically Computer Science fields with a strong passion.

I coded my first game when I was in 5th grade (a 2D Version of RuneScape), and built my first database-driven website a few years later.

I've been working freelance in this amazing field since I was about 15 years old.

My #1 honed skill is my ability to learn quickly, and I've spent years being able to go into a company, figure out what I need to know, and then learn it thoroughly, fast.

I hope to have the chance to show you how much I love this field, and how helpful I can be when given the opportunity.

Looking forward to hearing from you!

Best regards, Lance Madden Passionate Web Developer Founder, Gloucester Mass Marketing

Fastest Way to Reach Me: (978) 704-5900

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

Work Experience

Web Developer

Freelance - Boston, MA

February 2010 to Present

Whether it was reading my first book on HTML, building my own LAMP Servers for hosting PHP-backed, database-driven websites, or building SPA's with React, I've always been in love with Web Development.

Web Development is my bread and butter, and I've been working in the back-end for as long as I can remember.

Nowadays, I spend a lot of time working with Laravel & React as my back/front-end frameworks, but I'm very comfortable with the behind-the-scenes barebones PHP and JavaScript that powers some of these amazing frameworks.

There's really no other field I love enough to want to spend my days and nights improving my skills in for as long as possible.

Give me a chance to prove my learning, and adaptability capabilities, and you won't regret it.

Digital Marketing Manager

Gloucester Mass Marketing - Salem, MA March 2017 to August 2022

I founded Gloucester Mass Marketing in 2017, and for 5 years, I spent my time building websites, landing pages, and customer-acquisition systems for small businesses around the world.

I've spent over \$100,000 dollars on Facebook Ads, and I know the Facebook Ad & Google Ad Platforms like the back of my hand.

The majority of my clients were face-to-face small business owners, and during the COVID Pandemic, everything changed for my business.

Nowadays, I take on clients here and there, but the core focus of the work I spend my time on is in the Web Development field.

Head of Variable Data Development

Shawmut Communications Group - Danvers, MA October 2015 to February 2018

Head of Variable Data Development:

- Handle research into new Variable Data Print Technologies and their applications within Shawmut.
- Develop Automation Systems for handling the processing and final output(s) for repeat projects, from beginning-to-end.
- Meet with Prospective Clients as well as Current Clients to discuss Variable Data Print options, and possible ways to increase customer engagement within their company.
- Co-Creator of our powerful in-house database analyzing application, built primarily with JavaScript and the Node.js Framework.

Head Variable Data Specialist :																																	

- Process many different formats of incoming databases (.csv, .xls., .xlsx, .dbase, .dbf, .txt, .sql, & more) for Variable Data Development.

- Develop logic for Variable Data Projects, such as scripts to control dynamic text, layers, imagery, styling, and graphics, that will placed on the final print piece (based on information in the database).
- Create Highly Personalized Print Pieces using the Adobe Creative Suite, Adobe InDesign, and an Internationally Recognized Variable Data Management Plugin developed by Hewlett-Packard (A recent alumni appeal letter had upwards of 30+ logical conditions & 700+ possible final message combinations, delivering an extremely personal piece of mail).
- Script Development for the Handwriting.io API which allows the creation of 1-10000+ Digitally Handwritten PDFs, very quickly, using the information within a Client-Supplied Database, and a wide-array of different Handwriting Fonts.
- Front-to-End Mail Processing with BCC Mail Manager FS, including De-Duping, CASS Certification, NCOA Processing, Presorted Mailings, Batch Presorting, Commingling, SCF / NDA Drops, Bulk International Mail Processing
- Create and Impose Variable Data PDF Print Pieces for the HP Indigo 5500/7600 Digital Printers.

Education

\$40,000 + 1,200 Hours in Digital Advertising, Social Media Marketing, & Sales

Digital Marketing and Sales Courses - Nationwide

February 2014 to Present

Active Daily Self-Taught Learning in Computer Science

February 2007 to Present

2 Years in Computer Science

Wentworth Institute of Technology - Boston, MA June 2012 to June 2014

Skills

- Facebook Advertising (4 years)
- Web Development (10+ years)
- Marketing (10+ years)
- Email Marketing (4 years)
- Digital Marketing (5 years)
- Social Media Marketing (5 years)
- Javascript (10+ years)
- Ecommerce (10+ years)
- SEO (10+ years)
- InDesign (2 years)
- Microsoft Office (10+ years)
- Google Adwords (4 years)
- Wordpress (10+ years)
- Advertising (10+ years)
- Google Analytics (10+ years)

- Social Media (5 years)
- MySQL
- Analytics
- Adobe Creative Suite
- HTML5 (4 years)
- SEM
- Computer Networking
- AJAX
- Apache
- Git
- PHP (10+ years)

Links

http://gloucestermassmarketing.com

http://lancemadden.com

https://nextcodeproject.com

Certifications and Licenses

Certified Highly Recommended Local Business via Alignable

April 2018 to Present

1st Degree Black Belt

June 2010 to Present

I spend 9 years dedicated to this art, and traveled to test all over the country in order to earn my 1st Degree Black Belt.

Assessments

Social Media — Highly Proficient

May 2019

Measures a candidate's ability to create content, communicate online, and build a brand's reputation. Full results: <u>Highly Proficient</u>

Search Engine Optimization — Highly Proficient

August 2020

Interpreting online website performance metrics and understanding search engine optimization tactics Full results: <u>Highly Proficient</u>

Verbal Communication — Expert

August 2020

Speaking clearly, correctly, and concisely

Full results: Expert

Typing — Expert

August 2020

Transcribing text using a standard keyboard

Full results: Expert

Technical Support: Customer Situations — Highly Proficient

August 2020

Responding to technical support situations with sensitivity

Full results: <u>Highly Proficient</u>

Sales Skills — Highly Proficient

August 2020

Influencing and negotiating with customers

Full results: Highly Proficient

Indeed Assessments provides skills tests that are not indicative of a license or certification, or continued development in any professional field.

Additional Information

- I'm a huge nerd.
- I got my start building video games in elementary school, and I love playing them as well.
- I only drive Standard-Transmission vehicles, and have a strong enthusiasm for German Engineering.